{
  "reference_number": "12946",
  "clauses": [
    {
      "question": "1. What process should the Government use to set a new emissions reduction target in legislation?",
      "question_index": 0,
      "answer": "The Government sets a goal to reach net zero emissions by the second half of the century and the Climate Change Commission advises on the specific target for the Government to set later",
      "answer_index": 11,
      "notes": "This sort of change is something that takes place over time bit by bit, if you set it immediately I can see it being ignored and no\n change happening."
    },
    {
      "question": "2. If the Government sets a 2050 target now, which is the best target for New Zealand?",
      "question_index": 1,
      "answer": "Net Zero Emissions - Net zero emissions across all greenhouse gases by 2050",
      "answer_index": 1,
      "notes": "We need to be actually reversing what we currently have in the atmosphere, and everyone needs to take part, no favoritism. Creating\n\n targets and legislation immediately, despite having all the answers is the only way to see change in science, innovation and\n investment."
    },
    {
      "question": "3. How should New Zealand meet its targets?",
      "question_index": 2,
      "answer": "Domestic emissions reductions only (including from new forest planting)",
      "answer_index": 7,
      "notes": "I believe each country should be doing their part separately. Some may be in credit for example which shows a reversal from their\n hard work."
    },
    {
      "question": "4. Should the Zero Carbon Bill allow the 2050 target to be revised if circumstances change?",
      "question_index": 3,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "It needs to be revised in the sense that what is considered a carbon credit with the trading scheme because science is developing\n\n different methods of carbon sequestration. The target should never reach less than zero."
    },
    {
      "question": "5. The Government proposes that three emissions budgets of five years each (i.e. covering the next 15 years) be in place at any given time. Do you agree with this proposal?",
      "question_index": 15,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": "I think 5 years is too long, people, businesses and industry will wait until the last year or two to implement their strategy, and there is\n\n potential for failure."
    },
    {
      "question": "6. Should the Government be able to alter the last emissions budget (i.e. furthest into the future)?",
      "question_index": 4,
      "answer": "Yes - each incoming Government should have the option to review the third budget in the sequence",
      "answer_index": 14,
      "notes": "It should always be under review as long as the process is not held up."
    },
    {
      "question": "7. Should the Government have the ability to review and adjust the second emissions budget within a specific range under exceptional circumstances? See p36 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 5,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "Review should always take place."
    },
    {
      "question": "8. Do you agree with the considerations we propose that the Government and the Climate Change Commission take into account when advising on and setting budgets? See p44 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 6,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "9. Should the Zero Carbon Bill require Governments to set out plans within a certain timeframe to achieve the emissions budgets?",
      "question_index": 7,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "10. What are the most important issues for the Government to consider in setting plans to meet budgets? For example, who do we need to work with, what else needs to be considered?",
      "question_index": 8,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "I think government needs to include academic both from environmental and industries. If you only take on one or another you don't\n\nget balance necessary to create something that works."
    },
    {
      "question": "11. The Government has proposed that the Climate Change Commission advises on and monitors New Zealand's progress towards its goals. Do you agree with these functions? See p42 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 9,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "Absolutely you need a commission on this all important issue."
    },
    {
      "question": "12. What role do you think the Climate Change Commission should have in relation to the New Zealand Emissions Trading Scheme (NZ ETS)?",
      "question_index": 10,
      "answer": "Advising the Government on policy settings in the NZ ETS",
      "answer_index": 6,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "13. The Government has proposed that Climate Change Commissioners need to have a range of essential and desirable expertise. Do you agree with the proposed expertise? See p45 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 11,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "I agree with your range of expertise, but I have many of those attributes but am also employed by an industry player. Would that\n\nexclude me, because I hope it would not."
    },
    {
      "question": "14. Do you think the Zero Carbon Bill should cover adapting to climate change?",
      "question_index": 12,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "Currently yes, because we (as in humanity) is not making big enough change quickly enough and we are now faced with many\nclimate change issues that are only going to continue to get worse, especially with inaction from countries with major contributions to\n\nthe current GHG levels."
    },
    {
      "question": "15. The Government has proposed a number of new functions to help us adapt to climate change. Do you agree with the proposed functions? See p47 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 13,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "16. Should we explore setting up a targeted adaptation reporting power that could see some organisations share information on their exposure to climate change risks?",
      "question_index": 14,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "Do you have any other comments you'd like to make?",
      "question_index": 16,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "I think it is crucial that the ETS allow for more carbon credits than just with forestry. Particularly with agriculture when there are various\n\nforms of carbon farming that sequesters GHG in leaching, runoff, and volitisation into the atmosphere. I currently work for that\nindustry, and I spend much of my time researching carbon sequestration both at a personal level and I'm about to start with a\n\nuniversity and hopefully government as a consequence. I believe that this matter is urgent and we all need to work together to make\nthis reduction happen quickly, which is why I am currently employed in the main polluting industry. I hope to engage in discussion on\n\nthis topic further so please feel free to contact me.\n\n\n\n You have elected to withhold your personal details from publication."
    }
  ]
}
